<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <id>tag:photography.tutsplus.com,2005:/categories/blog</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://photography.tutsplus.com"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://photography.tutsplus.com/categories/blog.atom"/>
    <title>Tuts+ Photo &amp; Video - Blog</title>
    <updated>2014-12-29T10:35:16Z</updated>
    <entry>
        <id>tag:photography.tutsplus.com,2005:PostPresenter/cms-22835</id>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://design.tutsplus.com/articles/2014-a-year-in-tuts-content--cms-22835"/>
        <title>2014: A Year in Tuts+ Content</title>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As the year draws to a close, it's the perfect time to step back, take stock of what's happened in the past twelve months, and plan ahead (at least, that's what &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/trends/explore#q=%22year%20in%20review%22" target="_self"&gt;most people think&lt;/a&gt;). And there's one thing we do at Tuts+ in great quantity that gives us plenty to reflect upon: publishing content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/48/posts/22835/image/lookingback.gif"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the past twelve months, we've published&amp;nbsp;2,500 new articles and tutorials, and over 200&amp;nbsp;courses, from hundreds of different instructors, in our ten different topic areas. We've merged topics, introduced new functionality, and improved various aspects behind the scenes for our instructors.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Direction &amp;amp; Focus&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year has been about consolidating and better focusing some of our content. We're investing more than ever in our main topics—&lt;a href="https://code.tutsplus.com" target="_self"&gt;Code&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://design.tutsplus.com" target="_self"&gt;Design &amp;amp; Illustration&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://webdesign.tutsplus.com" target="_self"&gt;Web Design&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://photography.tutsplus.com" target="_self"&gt;Photo &amp;amp; Video&lt;/a&gt;. These have become the content areas that we've doubled down on, for both courses and tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's meant scaling back and merging sub-topics in some other areas, such as 3D &amp;amp; Motion Graphics, Music &amp;amp; Audio, and Craft (although we're still continuing to publish tutorial content in those topics every week).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a result, we've been able to invest more time and attention into our four core topics, and make them as fantastic as we possibly can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Looking at the Numbers&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's been a busy 12 months at Tuts+, and we're excited to share a few of the numbers around the content we've published. Between December 2013 and November 2014 (inclusive), we've added:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;over 2,500 new articles and tutorials&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;over 200 new courses&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;over 4 million words (roughly four times the length of the entire Harry Potter series)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;over 450 hours of courses (over two and a half weeks watched back to back)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;over 450 instructors (with 200 of them being brand new to Tuts+)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;We now have a total of almost 19,000 tutorials and 450 courses on Tuts+. There's a lot to learn!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure data-video-embed="true" data-original-url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lCrBtNxHoFI" class="embedded-video"&gt;
            &lt;iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/lCrBtNxHoFI?rel=0" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2&gt;It's Easier to Find What You're Looking For&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After publishing thousands of tutorials from different instructors and editors, our content categorisation needed some work! We took the time this year to begin cleaning up how we categorise all our courses and tutorials, and make sure they stay consistent in the future.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You'll now find &lt;a href="https://design.tutsplus.com/categories" target="_self"&gt;our category pages&lt;/a&gt; to be much more usable, as well as seeing helpful links between relevant tutorials and courses when browsing the site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;A Better Instructor Experience&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've thought carefully this year about the experience of being an instructor at Tuts+, from the on-boarding process for new instructors through to creating an instructor community, providing a better writing experience, and helping people stay up-to-date with what's happening at Tuts+.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amongst other things, we've finished rolling out a completely custom CMS for tutorials, an instructor discussion forum, and an improved process for getting help when creating a course. We're also sending out a monthly instructor newsletter to everyone who's contributed to Tuts+ in the past.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's never been a better time to begin teaching at Tuts+, and it's &lt;a href="https://tutsplus.com/teach" target="_self"&gt;simple to get started&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Your Favourite Courses&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last 12 months we've published more than 200 new courses, but which ones were the most popular? Here are your favourite courses published in the last year in each topic (not including our &lt;a href="http://tutsplus.com/courses?filter=free&amp;amp;page=1" target="_self"&gt;large selection of free courses&lt;/a&gt;, as they had an unfair advantage):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://code.tutsplus.com/courses/chrome-developer-tools" target="_self"&gt;Chrome Developer Tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design &amp;amp; Illustration:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://design.tutsplus.com/courses/advanced-vector-portraits" target="_self"&gt;Advanced Vector Portraits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Design:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://webdesign.tutsplus.com/courses/bombproof-web-design" target="_self"&gt;Bombproof Web Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photo &amp;amp; Video:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://photography.tutsplus.com/courses/what-every-photographer-should-know-about-lenses" target="_self"&gt;What Every Photographer Should Know About Lenses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Monochrome portrait by Sharon Milne from Advanced Vector Portraits" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/48/posts/22835/image/Monochrome-Portrait.jpg"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The monochrome portrait you'll learn to create in Sharon Milne's &lt;a href="http://design.tutsplus.com/courses/advanced-vector-portraits" target="_self"&gt;Advanced Vector Portraits&lt;/a&gt; course&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Translation Project&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the first time this year, we've begun to have Tuts+ tutorials translated into different languages, to better serve our audience around the world. At the time of writing, we now have over 500 posts in 27 different languages!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of this is down to our &lt;em&gt;incredible&lt;/em&gt; community of Tuts+ readers and instructors, who have been helping with the project. Thank you to everyone who's taken the time to translate a tutorial, and contributed to the project! If you're interested in finding out more, we have a few related blog posts that you might like to read:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://webdesign.tutsplus.com/articles/were-translating-tuts--cms-22522"&gt;We’re Translating Tuts+!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://webdesign.tutsplus.com/articles/5-things-i-learned-from-the-tuts-translation-project--cms-22520"&gt;5 Things I Learned From the Tuts+ Translation Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://webdesign.tutsplus.com/articles/the-tuts-translation-project-is-working-and-i-have-graphs-to-prove-it--cms-22662"&gt;The Tuts+ Translation Project Is Working, and I Have Graphs to Prove It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://code.tutsplus.com/articles/meet-erick-patrick-who-has-translated-50-tutorials-for-tuts--cms-22500"&gt;Meet Erick Patrick, Who Has Translated 50 Tutorials for Tuts+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What's Coming in 2015?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next year, we're going to maintain our focus on content. We'll be experimenting with new types of teaching (including live video interviews and discussions), exploring exciting new areas like 3D printing and drone photography, and continuing to improve how our tutorials and courses interconnect.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll be scaling up translations to offer more content than ever, in more languages than ever. And it goes without saying that we'll be working on a few larger, exciting projects that we can't announce yet!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks for being one of our readers, and for using Tuts+ to further your education and career. We hope you'll enjoy everything we have in store for 2015!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What Would You Like to See?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We're always interested in your ideas and feedback about how we can publish content that you'd love to watch, read, and learn from. What would you like to see in 2015, and how can we make Tuts+ better? Have your say in the comments below, or&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://tutsplus.uservoice.com/forums/248750-suggest-a-tuts-course-topic" target="_self"&gt;suggest a course&lt;/a&gt; you'd like to see!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <media:content url="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/48/posts/22835/preview_image/lookingback-thumb.png" medium="image" width="200" height="138"/>
        <published>2014-12-29T10:35:16.000Z</published>
        <updated>2014-12-29T10:35:16.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>David Appleyard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>tag:photography.tutsplus.com,2005:PostPresenter/cms-22690</id>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://design.tutsplus.com/articles/being-part-of-the-tuts-community--cms-22690"/>
        <title>Being Part of the Tuts+ Community</title>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whatever I've done online, I've always been part of a community. Tuts+ has an active community and there are many ways you can take part. Here I talk about community, what we've been doing, and how you can be a part of it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What Is a "Community"?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've always been active in the vector community, whether it’s been to talk about vector art or just to socialise. Many a night I used to be found online, in a chat room with fellow vector artists, discussing the latest trends, sharing links to artists we'd recently come across, or saying what pizza topping we were ordering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst others may have their own preconceptions of what a community is, to me, a community exists when there is a platform of communication. Communities can be complex and have their own forums and systems, or they can be as simple as a conversation thread on a tutorial, similar to what happens here on Tuts+.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Being Part of a Community&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being part of a community can reap many benefits, especially within creative fields. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is the obvious benefit of being able to “network” and get your name out there in the circles you travel in, but it’s not just about that. Being part of any community, you come across like-minded people, and perhaps meet people you end up forming great friendships with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I firmly believe if it wasn't for the vector community, I wouldn't be doing the job I am doing now. The experience I've gained and the connections I've made have all given me essential skills for being part of Tuts+.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, all this being said, you can’t just join a community and expect a job and someone to advise you on pizza toppings. Most creative communities will welcome you with open arms… new members are always welcome. But what you get out of the community depends on you. Some communities may be harder than others to be a part of, but don’t let that stop you!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Community Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst you can take part in discussions in the comments of tutorials, there are other ways you can be part of the community. Within the Design &amp;amp; Illustration section, we often post &lt;a href="http://design.tutsplus.com/categories/community-projects" target="_self"&gt;community projects&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Designers Graveyard Jenny Le" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/33/posts/22690/image/Jenny-Le_gravestone.jpg"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Designers Graveyard Project: Entry by &lt;a href="http://jennyle88.deviantart.com/" target="_self"&gt;Jenny Le&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;I love community projects as they're a chance for everyone, regardless of their skill level, to exercise their creative muscle or simply show off. I always make sure I take part in our projects as I need to keep pushing my own skills. It's been great seeing "Team Awesome" take part in these challenges also (Team Awesome is the name I give to the Design &amp;amp; Illustration Instructor team, and you'll find out why in a moment).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Skull designs by Tysia00 Lindsey Henderson Annika Dijana Devi" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/33/posts/22690/image/21-24-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Skull Challenge designs by: Tysia00, &lt;a href="http://intown-creative.blogspot.ca/" target="_self"&gt;Lindsey Henderson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.behance.net/hippyann" target="_self"&gt;Annika&lt;/a&gt;, Dijana Dević&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Team Awesome&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Team Awesome" is the name I give to the regular Design &amp;amp; Illustration instructor team. I call them this because they simply are awesome. Their willingness to take part in projects and themes and to help the community make them a great group of people to work with in providing quality content to the wider community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Tutorial Collaboration&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tuts+ has its own community, and it’s been great being part of it as a reader, then an instructor, and now an editor. What I've especially enjoyed taking part in are collaborations. Collaboration and community go hand in hand, and this has worked well with our instructors. Whether it’s been collaborating with an instructor from another section of Tuts+ or within the same area, the end results are always impressive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Asher Benson vs Sharon Milne - Queen of Hearts " src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/33/posts/22690/image/queenofhearts-small.jpg"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Asher Benson vs Sharon Milne: &lt;a href="http://design.tutsplus.com/tutorials/creating-a-queen-of-hearts-playing-card-through-collaboration--vector-6788" target="_self"&gt;Queen of Hearts&lt;/a&gt; tutorial&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;What usually happens is, there is an event coming up (such as Halloween, the summer, winter, someone is ordering a pizza), or someone from the community wants to learn something specific. This idea is then passed to the instructors to see what they can come up with.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Monika Zagrobelnas Mesh Skull" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/33/posts/22690/image/skull_final.png"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href="http://design.tutsplus.com/tutorials/using-meshes-to-create-a-detailed-skull-with-adobe-illustrator--vector-14848" target="_self"&gt;Using Meshes to Create a Detailed Skull With Adobe Illustrator&lt;/a&gt; by Monika Zagrobelna&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Team Awesome are always happy to take on suggestions from the community, especially when it leads to collaboration. In "real life" situations, especially in larger projects, you'll find more than one person is part of the creative process. So why not bring this into tutorials?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Miss ChatZs Decorated Skull" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/33/posts/22690/image/22_tut_illustrator_cc_skull_collab_by_miss_chatz1-sm.jpg"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href="http://design.tutsplus.com/tutorials/create-dia-de-los-muertos-decorations-on-a-skull-in-adobe-illustrator--vector-15901" target="_self"&gt;Create "Dia De Los Muertos" Decorations on a Skull in Adobe Illustrator&lt;/a&gt; by Miss Chat*Z&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Vector Battles&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Two Artists Enter, Both Leave… But There Is a Winner!&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over on art community websites, such as deviantART, “groups” focused on vector art brought together the community further, and made it easier for people to share new work with each other. As these groups became more complex, the level of interaction increased. This led to “Vector Battles”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vector Battles are when two artists go head to head on the same theme, within a set amount of time. The community (aka the people within the group) then vote for their favourite and a winner is decided. No prize is won other than bragging rights. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year I was brought into a conversation about community and it got me reminiscing about Vector Battles and the benefits of taking part in one. You've got the camaraderie aspect of it, but there’s also the competition aspect. When you’re in a competing frame of mind, you want to bring your best work to the table. It pushes you to be the best you can, and it may even force you to dig your heels in and be more creative, given you’re working towards a fixed theme.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Vector Battles on Tuts" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/33/posts/22690/image/Header.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Two Instructors Enter, Both Leave… But the Community Wins!&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The concept of design battles in general is not a unique one. I’ve seen it happen on many platforms, so how about bringing it to Tuts+? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Design &amp;amp; Illustration instructor team we have are not only very talented, but they also socialise together. They actively participate in Community Challenges, they talk to readers in comments and help them with any questions they may have, and away from Tuts+, they’re sharing each other’s new work and even gossiping&amp;nbsp;with each other on&amp;nbsp;Skype.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I asked whether they’d be interested in doing Vector Battles… and a couple of months later, we finished our first battle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The premise was that they were given a theme, they wrote a tutorial, and the end result had to follow the theme. They were both paid as they would usually be for their content, and we went through several rounds of voting. There were three rounds to be precise: an Editor vote (me!), a Guest Judge vote, and the Community vote.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Mary Winklers Gem Swapping UI" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/33/posts/22690/image/Crush-039.jpg"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href="http://design.tutsplus.com/tutorials/how-to-design-a-gem-swapping-mobile-game-ui-in-illustrator--cms-19862" target="_self"&gt;How to Design a Gem Swapping Mobile Game UI in Illustrator&lt;/a&gt; by Mary Winkler&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially there was going to be an instructor vote and a community vote, but to me, the instructors are very much part of the community, so why differentiate between them? We’re just as active in comments as anyone else is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can read about the &lt;a href="http://design.tutsplus.com/articles/vector-battle-round-one-diamonds-start--cms-20523" target="_self"&gt;start&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://design.tutsplus.com/articles/vector-battle-round-one-diamonds-game-over--cms-20739" target="_self"&gt;finish&lt;/a&gt; of the battle and find out who won when regular instructors &lt;a href="http://tutsplus.com/authors/mary-winkler" target="_self"&gt;Mary Winkler&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://tutsplus.com/authors/yulia-sokolova" target="_self"&gt;Yulia Sokolova&lt;/a&gt; went head to head with the theme of "diamonds and crystals".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Yulia Sokolovas Flat Precious Gems " src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/33/posts/22690/image/Diamond_tutorial_600.jpg"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href="http://design.tutsplus.com/tutorials/create-a-set-of-flat-precious-gems-icons-in-adobe-illustrator--vector-26188" target="_self"&gt;Create a Set of Flat Precious Gems Icons in Adobe Illustrator&lt;/a&gt; by Yulia Sokolova&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Join the Tuts+ Community&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are many ways you can take part in the community. It can start by simply engaging with our instructors in conversation threads on tutorials. If you want to take it that step further, join in on our &lt;a href="http://design.tutsplus.com/categories/community-projects" target="_self"&gt;Community Projects&lt;/a&gt;. And if you think you can kick it up a notch, why not consider &lt;a href="http://tutsplus.com/teach" target="_self"&gt;joining our regular instructor teams&lt;/a&gt;? I may see you soon as part of Team Awesome!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <media:content url="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/48/posts/22690/preview_image/Community-preview-queen.jpg" medium="image" width="200" height="138"/>
        <published>2014-12-12T12:08:14.000Z</published>
        <updated>2014-12-12T12:08:14.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Sharon Milne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>tag:photography.tutsplus.com,2005:PostPresenter/cms-22703</id>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://webdesign.tutsplus.com/articles/8-lessons-ive-learned-about-using-google-analytics-at-scale--cms-22703"/>
        <title>8 Lessons I’ve Learned About Using Google Analytics at Scale</title>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Like many websites, we use &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/"&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt; to track data about our visitors and what they do on our sites. However, Tuts+ is a fair bit bigger than a lot of those sites, and at our size, we run into a few problems using it. Here's what I've learned about working with Google Analytics at scale.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;
            &lt;span class="sectionnum"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Slice Data Into Smaller Date Ranges to Deal With Sampling Issues&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Google Analytics will only return 500,000 rows of data for any query you send it (with a few exceptions). If you make a request where the result covers more than this amount of data, Google Analytics will take a &lt;em&gt;sample&lt;/em&gt; of 500,000 rows, and multiply it up as necessary. &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;For example, if you have five million visitors in September, and you ask Google Analytics for a report on where those visitors came from across the month, Google Analytics will select 10% of the data it has about your September visitors, figure out where those 10% of visitors came from, and multiply those numbers by 10 to generate the report it gives you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Slice the data" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/48/posts/22703/image/1.Slice.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;This type of extrapolation is a common statistical technique, and a reasonable way for Google to cut down on processing time. Unfortunately, in my experience, the resulting reports can be misleading, or just plain wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The solution, for getting accurate data, is to ask for multiple slices of data over shorter date ranges, and then stitch them back together. Carrying on with the above example: if you have five million visitors in September, then you have around 500,000 visitors every three days. This means that if you make ten queries, each asking for three days' worth of data, each three-day report Google Analytics gives you will be completely unsampled. Stitch these back together, and you have unsampled data for the whole of the month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;
            &lt;span class="sectionnum"&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt; Learn to Use the API&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/web"&gt;Google Analytics web interface&lt;/a&gt; is powerful, and great for exploring your data, getting a rough idea of the numbers, or quickly sharing a report with colleagues. However, slicing the data into shorter time periods, downloading it, and putting it back together via the web interface is a time-consuming, error-prone pain in the neck.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;It's much easier to do this via the &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/reporting/core/v3/"&gt;Core Reporting API&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="https://ga-dev-tools.appspot.com/explorer/"&gt;Query Explorer&lt;/a&gt; is a fairly friendly way to get started constructing queries, and it's straightforward to go from there to grabbing data using Python, or another programming language.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;
            &lt;span class="sectionnum"&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt; Store Your Downloaded Google Analytics Data in an Actual Database&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Since you have to stitch these slices of data back together locally, you might as well store them in a central place where you can query and use them later. I use a clone of the Tuts+ back-end database, modified to add additional tables for Google Analytics data; this means that I can pair the traffic data to the relevant article, rather than to the URL (which is important, as our canonical URLs have changed over the years).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Store in a database" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/48/posts/22703/image/3.-Store.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="sectionnum"&gt;It also means that I can run complex queries like "show me the 100 posts with the most pageviews over the past month within a specific set of categories", or "get the most popular post from each instructor that has published at least five posts". It's difficult to do this with Google Analytics alone, since it doesn't understand our concepts of "category" or "instructor". Another advantage to having everything in a single database is that it's a lot easier to get it into external analysis and visualization tools like &lt;a href="http://www.tableausoftware.com/products/desktop" target="_self"&gt;Tableau&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;
            &lt;span class="sectionnum"&gt;4.&lt;/span&gt; Make Use of Views&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;In Google Analytics, each &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2649553?hl=en" target="_self"&gt;reporting view&lt;/a&gt; has a limit of 10,000 API requests per day: that's the maximum number of times I can ping it to get some data via the API. We have 18,000 posts across Tuts+, so getting information for each one separately from a single view would take two days.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Ah, but views live inside a &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2649554" target="_self"&gt;property&lt;/a&gt;, and each property has a total limit of 50,000 API requests. So, we have our Tuts+ property set up with a set of views each containing all traffic info for a single topic (like &lt;a href="http://code.tutsplus.com/" target="_self"&gt;Code&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://webdesign.tutsplus.com/" target="_self"&gt;Web Design&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://business.tutsplus.com/" target="_self"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt;), and an additional view containing all traffic info for Tuts+ as a whole. This way, we can query the Code view when we want data about Code posts, the Web Design view when we want data about Web Design posts, and so on, and make the best use of the 50,000 query limit instead of being restricted to 10,000.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;
            &lt;span class="sectionnum"&gt;5.&lt;/span&gt; Get Broad Data, Then Narrow It Down&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href="http://tutsplus.github.io/tuts-translation-stats/map.html" target="_self"&gt;this interactive map showing where readers of our translated tutorials came from&lt;/a&gt;, I had to download pageviews-per-country stats for about 250 posts, ranging from brand new to six months old (an average of roughly 100 days), in day-long slices—that's a total of 25,000 days' worth of data.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;I could make 25,000 queries to Google Analytics, but I know that: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Some posts got no pageviews on some of those days. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Unlike pageviews-per-country, "overall pageviews" is never sampled.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;So I made a single query to Google Analytics for each of the 250 posts, requesting the overall pageviews for each day the post had been online. Then I made another query to Google Analytics for each post and for each &lt;em&gt;day&lt;/em&gt; that the post had more than zero pageviews, requesting pageviews-per-country. This massively reduced the number of queries I had to make overall, which sped things up and meant I wasn't burning through so much of our Google Analytics API quota.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Narrow down the data" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/48/posts/22703/image/5.Narrow.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;
            &lt;span class="sectionnum"&gt;6.&lt;/span&gt; Use Multithreading&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;I've found that it typically takes five or more seconds for Google Analytics to return the result of a single query. This means that making one request for each of our 18,000+ posts, one after the other, takes over 24 hours to process! This is why I do them in parallel instead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Use multithreading" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/48/posts/22703/image/6.-Multithreading.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="sectionnum"&gt;Google Analytics lets you submit up to ten API requests per second, so you can submit 50 requests within the five seconds it takes to process your first one. This means that big queues of requests can be processed 50 times faster than if you made the requests in serial, which turns a 24-hour wait into a lunch-break wait.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;
            &lt;span class="sectionnum"&gt;7.&lt;/span&gt; Make Sure You Can Pick Up Where You Left Off&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;If (or, rather, when) your code crashes, your internet connection drops, you use up all your Google Analytics API allowance, or something else goes wrong 90% of the way through downloading a huge set of data, you do not want to have to restart the download process.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Make sure you're saving the data to disk as you download it (rather than just storing it in memory), and make sure you can skip to wherever you left off when you start the download again.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;
            &lt;span class="sectionnum"&gt;8.&lt;/span&gt; Decouple the Code That Gets Data From Your Specific Requests&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;I used to just write a whole new purpose-built set of code whenever I wanted to request some data that I hadn't requested before, copied and pasted from previous scripts, but this was limiting and inflexible. &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Eventually, I coded a more general solution that took into account all the lessons I'd learned above, and that could read external definition files that specified the data I wanted to download, like this example for downloading pageview data for all of our posts:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre class="brush: javascript noskimlinks noskimwords"&gt;{
            "SQL": "
            SELECT id, slug, section, earliest_date_requiring_data
            FROM posts
            ORDER BY earliest_date_requiring_data ASC
            ",
            "Dimensions": "ga:date",
            "Metrics": "ga:pageviews",
            "Filters": "ga:pagePath=~^/(articles|tutorials)/{slug}",
            "Slicing": "Whole",
            "View": "{section}",
            "OutputTemplate": "{id},{ga:date},{ga:pageviews}",
            "OutputFile": "all_post_pageviews.csv",
            "StartDate": "{earliest_date_requiring_data}",
            "EndDate": "{LastSunday}",
            }&lt;/pre&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Okay, these files aren't exactly human-readable and user-friendly, but they are fairly simple to understand and create if you have a good grip of the Google Analytics API and the way that our database is structured. It means that I can create new sets of instructions without touching the underlying code that executes them, and I can improve the underlying code without worrying about messing up any of the regular data downloads.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;A lot of these tips feel as if they describe the common sense approach when I look at them now, and I can hardly believe that I wasn't handling our data downloads this way all along. But it's taken a lot of trial and error and frustration to reach this process that works for us; I hope that by sharing it I can help someone else bypass that.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <media:content url="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/48/posts/22703/preview_image/thumb.png" medium="image" width="200" height="138"/>
        <published>2014-12-04T11:41:26.000Z</published>
        <updated>2014-12-04T11:41:26.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Michael James Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>tag:photography.tutsplus.com,2005:PostPresenter/cms-22754</id>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://design.tutsplus.com/articles/the-life-of-a-tuts-editor-meet-sharon-milne--cms-22754"/>
        <title>The Life of a Tuts+ Editor: Meet Sharon Milne</title>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered what it's like to work remotely as a Tuts+ Editor? The latest Envato Stories is all about the life of Sharon Milne, Design &amp;amp; Illustration Editor for Tuts+. She lives in Newcastle upon Tyne in the United Kingdom and has been obsessed with vector for over 14 years.&amp;nbsp;Sharon works from her home most of the time, but recently visited the Envato headquarters in Melbourne, Australia.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure data-video-embed="true" data-original-url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HCWNXkfyxBA" class="embedded-video"&gt;
            &lt;iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/HCWNXkfyxBA?rel=0" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the Tuts+ Design &amp;amp; Illustration Editor, Sharon works with a team of instructors from all around the world, and still has time to make art (including&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://design.tutsplus.com/tutorials/create-a-purple-monochrome-portrait-for-spirit-day-in-adobe-illustrator--cms-22374" target="_self"&gt;this portrait&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;of fellow Envato-er Jordan McNamara)&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;pass on her considerable vector skills with&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://tutsplus.com/authors/sharon-milne" target="_self"&gt;stunning illustration courses&lt;/a&gt;. She also changes her hair colour more than anyone else at Envato!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;More Envato Stories&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meet &lt;a href="http://inside.envato.com/envato-stories-jordy-vandeput/" target="_self"&gt;Jordy Vandeput&lt;/a&gt; who teaches video production, Tuts+ Editorial Manager&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://inside.envato.com/envato-stories-david-appleyard/" target="_self"&gt;David Appleyard&lt;/a&gt;, or see all previous&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://inside.envato.com/tag/envato-stories/" target="_self"&gt;Envato Stories&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;episodes. There are more to come, so stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <media:content url="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22754/preview_image/sharon-milne-thumbnail.jpg" medium="image" width="200" height="138"/>
        <published>2014-11-26T21:00:41.000Z</published>
        <updated>2014-11-26T21:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Jess Hooper</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>tag:photography.tutsplus.com,2005:PostPresenter/cms-22718</id>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://design.tutsplus.com/articles/tell-us-what-you-think-win-prizes-tuts-annual-survey-2014--cms-22718"/>
        <title>Tell Us What You Think &amp;amp; Win Prizes: Tuts+ Annual Survey 2014 </title>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s back! The Tuts+ annual survey for 2014 is here and we want to know what you think.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In having your say you could also win from a fantastic prize pool worth a total of more than $20,000! Plus there’s a special offer from Shopify and New Relic for everyone that completes the survey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is your opportunity to tell us what you like, dislike and love about Tuts+. You can also help us shape the future of your online learning by letting us know the features that would assist you with online learning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.surveymonkey.com/s/tuts_survey_2014" target="_self"&gt;Get started now!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What can you win?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Grand Prize: Total Prize Value $17,516&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lifetime membership to &lt;a href="https://madefreshly.com/" target="_self"&gt;MadeFreshly&lt;/a&gt; Pro Plan (RRP $420/year)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.runscope.com/tutsplus" target="_self"&gt;Runscope&lt;/a&gt; team account for up to 25 team members and 500,000 requests per month (RRP $2148)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.uxpin.com" target="_self"&gt;UXPin&lt;/a&gt; Pro Plan yearly subscription (RRP $300)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A yearly license to &lt;a href="http://macaw.co/?ref=tuts" target="_self"&gt;Macaw&lt;/a&gt; (RRP $179)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;1 year designer membership to &lt;a href="http://pixelkit.com/membership-plans/" target="_self"&gt;PixelKit&lt;/a&gt; (RRP $39)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;$400 worth of PSD to HTML or PSD to WordPress services with &lt;a href="http://www.reliablepsd.com" target="_self"&gt;Reliable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;6 months of APM product up to 5 hosts with &lt;a href="http://newrelic.com/" target="_self"&gt;New Relic&lt;/a&gt; (RRP $4470)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.heartinternet.uk/?utm_source=tutsplus&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=survey" target="_self"&gt;Heart Internet&lt;/a&gt; VPS Plus SSDdrive 4 CPUs 50GB Space 5 GB Ram Plesk Control panel, 30 sites (RRP $1772)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A professional level shop for a year and a paid theme of your choice from &lt;a href="http://www.shopify.com/" target="_self"&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt; (RRP $1128)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A year for free on &lt;a href="https://motivapp.com" target="_self"&gt;Motiv&lt;/a&gt; (RRP $180)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;One year &lt;a href="http://www.adobe.com/au/creativecloud.html" target="_self"&gt;Adobe Creative Cloud&lt;/a&gt; licence (RRP $600)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Runner Up: Total Prize Value $1128&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;1 year membership to &lt;a href="https://madefreshly.com/" target="_self"&gt;MadeFreshly&lt;/a&gt; Pro Plan (RRP $420)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.uxpin.com" target="_self"&gt;UXPin&lt;/a&gt; Pro Plan yearly subscription (RRP $300)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A yearly license to &lt;a href="http://macaw.co/?ref=tuts" target="_self"&gt;Macaw&lt;/a&gt; (RRP $179)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;1 year designer membership to &lt;a href="http://pixelkit.com/membership-plans/" target="_self"&gt;PixelKit&lt;/a&gt; (RRP $39)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;6 Months free on &lt;a href="https://motivapp.com" target="_self"&gt;Motiv&lt;/a&gt; (RRP $90)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;$100 credit on &lt;a href="https://www.twilio.com/" target="_self"&gt;Twillio&lt;/a&gt; (RRP $100)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Honorable Mention: Total Prize Value $818&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;6 month membership to &lt;a href="https://madefreshly.com/" target="_self"&gt;MadeFreshly&lt;/a&gt; Pro Plan (RRP $210)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.uxpin.com" target="_self"&gt;UXPin&lt;/a&gt; Pro Plan yearly subscription (RRP $300)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A yearly license to &lt;a href="http://macaw.co/?ref=tuts" target="_self"&gt;Macaw&lt;/a&gt; (RRP $179)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;1 year designer membership to &lt;a href="http://pixelkit.com/membership-plans/" target="_self"&gt;PixelKit&lt;/a&gt; (RRP $39)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;6 Months free on &lt;a href="https://motivapp.com" target="_self"&gt;Motiv&lt;/a&gt; (RRP $90)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Editor Favourites&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;7x 1 year designer membership to &lt;a href="http://pixelkit.com/membership-plans/" target="_self"&gt;PixelKit&lt;/a&gt; (RRP $39 each)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;7x Tuts+ yearly subscriptions (RRP $180 each)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everyone that completes the survey will receive an offer from &lt;a href="http://www.shopify.com/" target="_self"&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://newrelic.com/" target="_self"&gt;New Relic&lt;/a&gt; via email after 10 December.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.surveymonkey.com/s/tuts_survey_2014" target="_self"&gt;Take the Tuts+ Annual Survey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A big thanks to all our sponsors!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22718/image/Tuts-Survey-Sponsors.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content>
        <media:content url="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22718/preview_image/tuts-2014-survey.png" medium="image" width="200" height="138"/>
        <published>2014-11-20T00:19:02.186Z</published>
        <updated>2014-11-20T00:19:02.186Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Nicole Bowes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>tag:photography.tutsplus.com,2005:PostPresenter/cms-22662</id>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://webdesign.tutsplus.com/articles/the-tuts-translation-project-is-working-and-i-have-graphs-to-prove-it--cms-22662"/>
        <title>The Tuts+ Translation Project Is Working, and I Have Graphs to Prove It</title>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over 100 volunteers have translated over 300 tutorials and articles into over 25 languages for the &lt;a href="https://tutsplus.com/translate-for-us" target="_self"&gt;Tuts+&amp;nbsp;Translation Project&lt;/a&gt;. That's remarkable, and I feel that this response from our community alone proves that the project is a worthwhile initiative. However, as a data analyst, it's my job to put my feelings to one side and explore how it's doing using numbers and graphs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Where in the World Are Our Readers?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To start digging into the data, &lt;a href="https://tutsplus.com/authors/ian-yates" target="_self"&gt;Ian Yates&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and I put together an&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://tutsplus.github.io/tuts-translation-stats/map.html" target="_self"&gt;interactive map&lt;/a&gt; showing the geographic profile of visitors to each translated post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tutsplus.github.io/tuts-translation-stats/map.html"&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Interactive Map of Global Traffic to Tuts Translated Tutorials" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22662/image/translation-map.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click on a translation, and the countries change colour. The darker green a country is, the more visitors the post got from there compared to other countries. The map also shows this information for all translated posts on aggregate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can see that different languages of post attract different geographical profiles of readers. This might not be surprising, but it's a very important result: it shows that the translations are reaching different areas of the world, not just people living in English-speaking countries that would prefer to read posts in a different language.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Where on the Web Do They Come From?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm also interested in how people are getting to the translated posts. We can categorise visits into two main paths: those that come from inside Tuts+, and those that come from outside Tuts+.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Pageviews for all translated posts split up by source" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22662/image/translation-traffic-from-base-post-vs-external-sources.png"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Pageviews for all translated posts, split up by source.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this graph, the yellow line represents all pageviews across all translated posts that the reader got to by clicking through from the English version of the post. (This is the only way we would realistically expect readers to navigate to translated posts from within Tuts+, as we don't yet have language-specific index pages.) The grey line represents all pageviews across all translated posts that the reader got to from an external source: a link on another site, a tweet, a Google search, a bookmark, or similar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's clear that far more people get to the translations from outside Tuts+ than from inside. This might indicate an issue with visibility (that is, many visitors might not be aware that so many posts have been translated into their languages), or it might simply be the case that people that prefer reading in languages other than English don't tend to visit Tuts+ (yet).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let's break this down further, and see which external sources bring people to the translated posts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Pageviews for all translated posts split up into specific external sources" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22662/image/entrances-by-medium_all-languages.png"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Pageviews for all translated posts, split up into specific external sources.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;June's spike in social media traffic is due to Ian publishing translations for a post that he already knew was very popular, and then promoting it heavily on Facebook and Twitter; it obviously spread! August's drop in social media traffic is due to Ian deciding to stop promoting translated posts on Twitter and Facebook after followers complained that these posts weren't relevant; this is a fair criticism, of course, but it's a pity that we don't have a better solution, as obviously a lot of people did find the translations relevant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's very reassuring to see that search traffic is steadily increasing. If people only found translations through the site or through our active promotion, and never organically through search, that would be a bad sign.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Search traffic for all translated posts vs number of translated posts published" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22662/image/search-traffic-vs-translations-published.png"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Search traffic for all translated posts vs. number of translated posts published over time.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here, the red line again represents total search traffic to translations, and the grey bars represent the number of translations on the site. We can see that there's an almost linear relationship between the number of translations we publish and the search traffic we get. It would be great to see more of an upward curve in that red line, but even just seeing the existing trend continue would be a good result, as there are plenty of tutorials left to translate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What Languages Are They Reading?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's also useful to break down the traffic landing on the translations by the language of the translations:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Pageviews landing on translated posts split up by language of the post" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22662/image/entrances_by_language.png"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Pageviews landing on translated posts, split up by language of the post.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spanish translations are in front by quite a margin, but I believe a lot of this is simply because we've published far more translations in Spanish than in almost any other language:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Number of translated posts in each language" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22662/image/translations_per_language.png"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Number of translated posts in each language.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can see that there are about half as many French translations as Spanish ones, and they get about half as much of the traffic; there are roughly half as many German and Russian translations as French ones, and again they get about half as much of the traffic. But this pattern doesn't hold for all of the languages: Portuguese and Indonesian are obvious exceptions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can chalk this up, at least partly, to the fact that there are fewer Portuguese speakers than Spanish speakers, and fewer Indonesian speakers than French or Russian speakers. The selection of posts that have been translated may also be a factor. But in at least one country's case, there's more to it than that...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;We Aren't Reaching China&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you've explored the &lt;a href="http://tutsplus.github.io/tuts-translation-stats/map.html" target="_self"&gt;interactive map&lt;/a&gt;, you may have noticed that clicking "Bulgarian" makes Bulgaria light up bright, "Hungarian" makes Hungary light up bright, "Swedish" makes Sweden light up bright, and so on, usually with a few other countries lighting up dimmer as well. Click on "Chinese (Traditional)" or "Chinese (Simplified)", however, and China does light up, but only dimly—no more than any other country on the map.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Kendra Schaefer explains in&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://webdesign.tutsplus.com/articles/notes-from-behind-the-firewall-the-state-of-web-design-in-china--cms-22281" target="_self"&gt;Notes From Behind the Firewall: The State of Web Design in China&lt;/a&gt;, it's not easy to get your website seen in China if it's hosted outside the mainland. This graph puts that in perspective:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Pageviews for all Chinese posts split up into specific external sources" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22662/image/chinese-translations_entrances-by-medium.png"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Pageviews for all Chinese posts, split up into specific external sources.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's another graph showing the number of people coming directly to the translations from external sources, using the same scale as the "Pageviews for all translated posts, split up into specific external sources"&amp;nbsp;graph, but this time it's filtered to show only the Chinese translations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The total traffic is low (hence the whitespace), yes, but the main point is that almost all of the traffic to our Chinese translations came from social media—and almost none from search—so when we stopped promoting translations on Twitter and Facebook, it became very unlikely that anyone would find the Chinese translations on their own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;In Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our tagline is "Teaching skills to millions worldwide", and the Tuts+ Translation Project is helping us do that. The results we've seen so far might not be surprising, but they are promising and reassuring.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having said that, this analysis has revealed several areas for improvement: making our existing visitors aware that we offer tutorials and articles in different languages; keeping regular readers updated on new tutorials and articles written in their preferred languages; and making headway in countries like China where we don't yet have a foothold.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <media:content url="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22662/preview_image/translationchart.png" medium="image" width="200" height="138"/>
        <published>2014-11-17T02:42:50.630Z</published>
        <updated>2014-11-17T02:42:50.630Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Michael James Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>tag:photography.tutsplus.com,2005:PostPresenter/cms-22646</id>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://code.tutsplus.com/articles/become-an-envato-meetup-host--cms-22646"/>
        <title>Become an Envato Meetup Host</title>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Inspired by your enthusiasm and support for Envato meetups over the years, and our desire to solve the one grumble about them (“Why can’t one be held in my town?”), we’re excited to announce the Envato Global meetup program, something everyone in the community can get involved in.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Envato Meetups are self-organized events for members of the Envato community. Whether you’re a learner on Tuts+, an author on Envato Market, or a client on Envato Studio, get together—talk shop, trade war stories, make new friends and see the faces behind the avatars. They can be casual, coffee-shop get togethers or epic full-day events—it’s up to you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the instructions below, then let us know if you’re keen to become an &lt;a href="https://envato.formstack.com/forms/envatomeetups_host" target="_self"&gt;Envato meetup host&lt;/a&gt;. We’re only taking expressions of interest at this stage to determine demand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Tuts and Envato Marketplaces London Meetup" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22646/image/Envato_Meetup_1.jpg"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The Tuts+/Envato London Meetup, 2014. See more photos on &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/we-are-envato/sets/72157638167643614/"&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How Would It Work?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Sign Up to Host or Attend a Meetup&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have a passion for the community, a bunch of creativity, and oodles of energy, sign-up to host an Envato meetup in your area. If one already exists simply pop along and get involved.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Promote The Meetup&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As host of your meetup it will be your responsibility to get word out, don’t worry though, we will help by tweeting about it from @envato.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Get Sweet Merch&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Request a merchandise kit, we will send every new meetup group a bag of goodies (laptop stickers, badges, nametags) in time for your first meetup. If your meetup continues to prosper we will keep the goodies coming with new and interesting stuff.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Tell Us Your Story&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tell us about it, send a story about your meetup as well as some photos of the attendees, and we’ll do our best to share across the Envato network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Envato Meetup San Francisco 2013 " src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22646/image/San_Fran_Meetup.jpg"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Envato's San Francisco Meetup, 2013. More images on &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/we-are-envato/sets/72157638529603276/"&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Interested?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If becoming an Envato meetup host is something you're keen to do, &lt;a href="https://envato.formstack.com/forms/envatomeetups_host" target="_self"&gt;register your interest today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <media:content url="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22646/preview_image/imgo-400.png" medium="image" width="200" height="138"/>
        <published>2014-11-10T03:06:20.434Z</published>
        <updated>2014-11-10T03:06:20.434Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Jess Hooper</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>tag:photography.tutsplus.com,2005:PostPresenter/cms-22499</id>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://photography.tutsplus.com/articles/envato-stories-meets-tuts-instructor-jordy-vandeput--cms-22499"/>
        <title>Envato Stories Meets Tuts+ Instructor Jordy Vandeput</title>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The latest&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://inside.envato.com/tag/envato-stories/" target="_self"&gt;Envato Stories&lt;/a&gt; video comes from Hasselt, Belgium, where the team met up with Tuts+ video production instructor &lt;a href="http://tutsplus.com/authors/jordy-vandeput" target="_self"&gt;Jordy Vandeput&lt;/a&gt;. Jordy has been teaching on Tuts+ since the start of 2013, as well as running his own video production company.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure data-video-embed="true" data-original-url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B9Ld6u2puRY" class="embedded-video"&gt;
            &lt;iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/B9Ld6u2puRY?rel=0" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since buying his first camera at the age of 12 Jordy has been passionate about filmmaking. In his teaching he gets the most out of knowing that he can help another person fulfil their ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His advice to those starting out is to always keep learning and practising and eventually it will come:&amp;nbsp;"Give it some time and never give up."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22499/image/jordy_2b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;To get started learning with Jordy, check out some of his courses for Tuts+:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cgi.tutsplus.com/courses/adobe-premiere-elements-essentials" target="_self"&gt;Adobe Premiere Elements Essentials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cgi.tutsplus.com/courses/getting-started-with-adobe-speedgrade" target="_self"&gt;Getting Started with Adobe SpeedGrade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://photography.tutsplus.com/courses/recording-video-with-a-dslr" target="_self"&gt;Recording Video With a DSLR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;More Envato Stories&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meet Tuts+ Editorial Manager&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://inside.envato.com/envato-stories-david-appleyard/" target="_self"&gt;David Appleyard&lt;/a&gt;, or see all previous&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://inside.envato.com/tag/envato-stories/" target="_self"&gt;Envato Stories&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;episodes. There are more to come, so stay tuned!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <media:content url="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22499/preview_image/jordy_3-1s.jpg" medium="image" width="200" height="138"/>
        <published>2014-10-24T04:44:49.879Z</published>
        <updated>2014-10-24T04:44:49.879Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Jess Hooper</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>tag:photography.tutsplus.com,2005:PostPresenter/cms-22500</id>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://code.tutsplus.com/articles/meet-erick-patrick-who-has-translated-50-tutorials-for-tuts--cms-22500"/>
        <title>Meet Erick Patrick, Who Has Translated 50 Tutorials for Tuts+</title>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The level of community participation since we began the &lt;a href="https://tutsplus.com/translate-for-us" target="_self"&gt;Tuts+ translation project&lt;/a&gt; six months ago has been truly overwhelming. 95 volunteers have seen their translations published, and the number of new participants grows with each passing week. Recently I caught up with Erick Patrick, our most prolific translator to date with over 50 published translations (and counting!) to ask him a few questions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="question"&gt;Hi Erick. Let’s kick this off—tell us a bit about yourself!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, my name is Erick Patrick, and I’m a 26-year-old Brazilian father, systems analyst and freelance web developer. Since the 2000’s I’ve been learning web development and programming. This got me to a BA in Computer Science and an application for a Masters in Biotechnology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Erick Patrick  Daughter" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22500/image/IMG_2802.JPG"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="question"&gt;To date you’ve translated over fifty Tuts+ tutorials into Portuguese—are you naturally a competitive person?!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sort of, I like to compete with myself! I set deadlines and goals based on last year’s achievements, always trying to get better year over year. I’m always hungry for new knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="question"&gt;You were translating tutorials and publishing them yourself before the Tuts+ translation project began. Is translating something you’d consider doing professionally?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, indeed. Now that I know how much and what I’m capable of, this is a great option for an alternative/second career. We should always be open to new possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="question"&gt;Given that this is an entirely voluntary scheme, what kind of reward do you get from translating tutorials?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plain and simple: knowledge, skill proficiency, networking and friendship! Through translating I’ve “met” some really amazing people who ask and give great advice, not only professionally, but in terms of life advice too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="question"&gt;Who do you think benefits from your translations?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite our growing community, there are lots of beginner/intermediate developers for whom language is a barrier. They know that most of the new and best content is in English, but they either don’t like the language, or have no means to learn and get better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="question"&gt;Are any aspects of translating particularly difficult?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;English phrasal verbs and expressions. Some of them are so unique that it’s really hard to find a translation that can express as much meaning as the original. And this is one reason I keep some terms in English.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Erick Patrick" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22500/image/IMG_2805.JPG"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p class="question"&gt;Do you have any words of advice for anyone else who’s thinking of translating tutorial content?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think of the long term benefits (knowledge, proficiency, etc). Be professional and do your best. Whether it’s paid or voluntary, it’s your name on the line.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Erick’s Five Most Popular Translations&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://code.tutsplus.com/pt/tutorials/object-oriented-php-for-beginners--net-12762" target="_self"&gt;PHP Orientado a Objetos Para Iniciantes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://code.tutsplus.com/pt/tutorials/laravel-4-a-start-at-a-restful-api-updated--net-29785" target="_self"&gt;Laravel 4: Começando com API RESTful&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://code.tutsplus.com/pt/tutorials/the-30-css-selectors-you-must-memorize--net-16048" target="_self"&gt;Os 30 Seletores CSS Que Você Deve Memorizar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://code.tutsplus.com/pt/tutorials/solid-part-1-the-single-responsibility-principle--net-36074" target="_self"&gt;Princípios SOLID Parte 1 - O Princípio da Responsabilidade Única&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://code.tutsplus.com/pt/tutorials/pdo-vs-mysqli-which-should-you-use--net-24059" target="_self"&gt;PDO ou MySQLi: Qual Você Deveria Usar?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;In The Wild&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/erickpatrick" target="_self"&gt;@erickpatrick on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.erickpatrick.net/" target="_self"&gt;Erick’s Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Want to join Erick and help translate Tuts+ into Português or any other language? Head over to the &lt;a href="https://tutsplus.com/translate-for-us" target="_self"&gt;translation information page&lt;/a&gt; to learn more.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <media:content url="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22500/preview_image/IMG_2805s.jpg" medium="image" width="200" height="138"/>
        <published>2014-10-17T05:20:55.000Z</published>
        <updated>2014-10-17T05:20:55.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Yates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>tag:photography.tutsplus.com,2005:PostPresenter/cms-22518</id>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://webdesign.tutsplus.com/articles/how-were-using-trello-to-simplify-our-editorial-process--cms-22518"/>
        <title>How We’re Using Trello to Simplify Our Editorial Process</title>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If there’s one thing at the heart of everything Tuts+ does, it’s people. We currently have ten editors and course producers who in turn team with a pool of managers, copy editors, assistants and analysts. Some of these editors work with as many as a hundred different instructors in a given year and from every corner of the globe. When you start multiplying those numbers together, it equates to a very large group of people, all working together to create tutorials and courses that are consistent in approach and quality. In concept, this is fairly simple. In execution, it’s no small feat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We use a number of communication and project management tools at Tuts+, but we recently rolled out a new and very specific workflow for planning, commissioning and revising our content. The goal—to make life better for everyone involved in the editorial side of Tuts+, so that we can make even more great things for you to learn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Consistency vs. Autonomy Tradeoff&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our editorial team is almost entirely remote (from HQ in Melbourne), scattered all over the globe in different timezones. The freedom to choose when and how to work is built into the job. It’s a significant perk and is a large part of why working for Tuts+ is so great. However, as the team grew and diversified over the years, workflows became more and more disparate and consequently so did the end product. It became obvious that if we wanted a more consistent and unified content strategy we needed to start operating more like a team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Happy Medium The Midpoint Between Micromanagement and Inconsistency" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22518/image/autonomytradeoffb.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once the need for change was recognised we spent months trying to find a balance between autonomy and consistency. Since then we’ve updated our processes and guidelines across the board and completely overhauled how we approach content planning and creation. A key part of this process was an in-depth examination and redefinition of our editorial commissioning workflow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;A Unified Editorial Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It became apparent that if we wanted to get everyone on the same page and provide a greater level of transparency for the content planning workflows of our entire team, we’d have to implement a consistent workflow across every topic and category.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inherently, that approach comes with some lofty goals. To be truly useful, it would have to track the status of every single tutorial and course published across the network, while also serving as an important documentation process for the major points of communication behind each individual piece of content. A fair amount of conversation and decision-making between editors and instructors goes into everything we publish, and it’s important to pull as much of this communication out of private email as possible, so that other team members can be involved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Planning the Process Before Choosing a Tool&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With such a wealth of project management, collaboration and editorial applications available these days, choosing a platform to take our team forward was more difficult than you’d imagine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best advice in this situation is: forget the software. Instead of looking for tools on which to base the new workflow, we instead built the workflow independent of any application, then looked around to see what fit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this stage it was necessary to distill the universal aspects of the editorial process down into clear steps. Each Tuts+ Editor has their own preferred methods and workflows. We had to ask ourselves: what steps does a tutorial or course&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;typically&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;take through its journey from conception to completion?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we arrived at a simple diagram which outlined the entire process. Regardless of how personalized and unique any editor’s workflow was, odds are, it included these basic steps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Tuts Editorial Workflow" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22518/image/workflowoutlineb.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Process of Elimination&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Armed with a clarified understanding of exactly how the system would work, we could now proceed to find a tool to facilitate the process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collaborative writing apps were out (we already have a CMS). We needed a communication tool, not a writing tool. Scalability and flexibility, however, were key. If we were to add over one hundred instructors, all working independently and having conversations with their editor, would the amount of content make the app difficult to use?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After applying these ideas and keeping the desired workflow in mind, one app stood out as the clear winner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Trello&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Right back when we embarked on improving our editorial process we looked at&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://trello.com/"&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt;, but dismissed it quickly because of its simplistic approach. The more we compared it with the diagram, however, the more it made sense to have each individual piece of content moving horizontally, back and forth through the workflow. If each tutorial were a card, and each step in the process were a list, participants could easily drag tutorials from one step to the next and track their progress as they moved through the system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Using Trello For Our Workflow" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22518/image/trelloboardb.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;It turns out that Trello only&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;appears&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;simplistic. Under the hood it’s hiding a truly impressive feature set. Here are some of the organizational features that help you cut through the clutter in Trello:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Filters&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Labels&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Due dates (and missed due date highlighting)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Robust search&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Assignees&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Username @ tagging (like on Twitter)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Notifications&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;An all-inclusive activity feed&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Calendar (organizes content by due date)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Visible card aging (makes cards fade after a period of inactivity)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like most project management tools, Trello allows you to assign specific people to a task (as many as you want) and apply due dates, which then serve to trigger reminders and notifications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The visual nature of each task is an important aspect of Trello. Assigned users’ avatars appear on cards, along with coloured labels for easy reference and attachment thumbnails for immediate identification. Lack of activity on a card will reduce its opacity, so anything which isn’t getting the attention it deserves will visibly begin to fade away. There’s even a colour-blind friendly mode which, when activated, distinguishes coloured areas by adding patterned backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lastly, and importantly for us, the volume of cards on a busy “board” can quickly be thinned by filtering based on person, subject, keyword and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In short, Trello fits very well with our desired editorial process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;It Isn’t Perfect&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;An important part of this entire process was in realizing that there wouldn’t be one single application built to our precise needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The key area we’ve found to be lacking in Trello is the ability to facilitate group discussions. In processes where group discussions take center stage, Basecamp is a far better solution that makes it much easier to kick off and keep track of a team conversation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That said, Trello does cultivate a sense of community. All members of a board, be they editors, managers or instructors, are made to feel that they’re welcome to engage on any task or conversation. Avatars put faces to names, discussions ensue and teams bonds are formed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2013, there was no single place where we could quickly and easily take the pulse of our entire body of upcoming content. Nor was there a quick way to hand off a topic area (including all in-progress content, all the relevant instructors, and future content plans) to a new editor, temporarily or permanently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now we have all of this and more, though implementing our new workflow was definitely a learning curve. Here are some of the most important lessons we came across along the way:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;In larger remote teams, there can be a significant tradeoff between autonomy and consistency. Finding the unique balance for your team and task is important, but not easy.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;In creating workflows for the entire team, it’s important to remove personal biases where possible and consider what works best for a diverse group of people performing a variety of tasks.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don’t find apps that you like and then use them to shape your team’s workflows. Build workflows that serve your purpose and then look for a tool that you can use to facilitate that process.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;No single existing tool will fit your needs perfectly; either build your own or be prepared to compromise by selecting the one that fits your primary purpose best.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don’t attach yourself to a process just because you’ve put a lot of work into it. Get feedback from the people who will actually use it every day and respond to their concerns. Sometimes this means defending an important pillar of the workflow, but more often it means admitting that you were wrong about something and being willing to make a change.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
        <media:content url="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22518/preview_image/trelloboardc.png" medium="image" width="200" height="138"/>
        <published>2014-10-08T05:38:49.000Z</published>
        <updated>2014-10-08T05:38:49.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Josh Johnson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>tag:photography.tutsplus.com,2005:PostPresenter/cms-22519</id>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://code.tutsplus.com/articles/in-praise-of-side-projects--cms-22519"/>
        <title>In Praise of Side Projects</title>
        <content type="html">&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Side Projects Introduction" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22519/image/sideprojects4b.gif"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you’ve got some useful creative or technical skills, plus a healthy work ethic—now what? Should you work in an established business? Become a freelancer or small business owner selling services to clients? Or invest in developing your own product business?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put another way, how can you best convert your skills and time into the outcomes you seek in life?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I’ve learned after trying out all three approaches. Your conclusions may be different to mine, but hopefully this perspective gets you thinking more broadly about the options you have available.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Time vs Money&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The traditional approach to work is to swap your time and skills for money,&amp;nbsp;andthen save&amp;nbsp;that money to invest in assets elsewhere. That’s the fundamental model underpinning employment and freelancing: put your skills to use for the benefit of someone else, and get paid cash in return.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But there’s another alternative: you could use your time and skills to build an asset directly. This is potentially more lucrative than a lifetime of earning and saving, and it’s what successful entrepreneurs do when they create intellectual property, products, and businesses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It sounds great… when it works. The downside is that new products and businesses are inherently risky.&amp;nbsp;Depending on&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://hbswk.hbs.edu/item/6591.html"&gt;who&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nielsen.com/us/en/insights/news/2014/how-to-flip-85-misses-to85-hits-lessons-from-the-nielsen-breakthrough-innovation-project.html"&gt;you&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.quora.com/Product-Management/Is-the-80-product-failure-rate-statistic-actually-true"&gt;believe&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://blogs.hbr.org/2014/09/the-silent-killer-of-new-products-lazy-pricing/"&gt;and&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.sba.gov/sites/default/files/sbfaq.pdf"&gt;how&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;you define failure, research suggests that 30% to 95% of new products and startups will fail.&amp;nbsp;Choosing between selling your time versus investing it in a product involves some critical trade-offs: near-term income vs long-term wealth, certainty vs risk, and resources vs autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Perils of All or Nothing&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The “&lt;a href="https://signalvnoise.com/posts/1078-it-doesnt-have-to-be-all-or-nothing-with-a-startup"&gt;all-or-nothing&lt;/a&gt;, burn the boats and go for it” approach that is sometimes glorified in startup culture is actually less common than it seems and can be unwise, particularly if (&lt;a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/krisztinaholly/2014/01/15/why-great-entrepreneurs-are-older-than-you-think/"&gt;like most successful entrepreneurs&lt;/a&gt;)&amp;nbsp;you’re a bit older and have other commitments like kids and a mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given the risk of new products, passion and commitment are necessary but not sufficient. There’s no shortage of failed entrepreneurs whose passion for a product fizzled out as they struggled to get customers to (i) notice it (ii) understand it, (iii) see value in it, and (iv) actually pay for it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know people who took that path and backed their new product with their life savings, only to go through the heartache of losing almost everything when the reality fell short of their expectations. Too many people burn through 90% of their resources to discover that they’re only half-way on the journey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s where side projects come in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;A Project on the Side&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The alternative approach to all-or-nothing is to invest a small amount of your time and money in a side project. You can do this out of hours, around your day job. Time is short, so you have to be disciplined and focused. By necessity it’s a bare-bones product (an&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://theleanstartup.com/principles"&gt;MVP&lt;/a&gt;, if you like)&amp;nbsp;but done properly it tests your core beliefs about what customers need and will pay for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The advantages of a side project are two-fold. First up, the downside is contained and manageable—you’re not betting the ranch on things having to work first time. If it goes pear-shaped, all you’ve lost is some of your spare time… and even then you’ll have learned an enormous amount.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Secondly, as the saying goes, “nothing ventured, nothing gained”. Now you&amp;nbsp;have a ticket to play the game, plus the option to expand your commitment if it makes sense to do so. You won’t be that guy or girl who’s always talking about their big ideas but never acting on them. With a side project, you are making progress on your product idea, so you can adapt and evolve your plans as you learn more about what customers really want. Once you get it right, you can expand your commitment accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Real With Options&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strategists refer to this approach as&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Real_options_valuation"&gt;real options&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;thinking. As in financial markets, an “option” gives you the right (but not the obligation) to take a particular course of action. There is a cost to acquiring this option, but you get access to the upside for only a fraction of the full investment upfront. Although there is a cost to execute the option and commit to the future action, the advantage is you make that decision later when you have better insights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This means that options tend to be worth more when they last a long time and are cheap to execute, and when the opportunity is big and the situation is uncertain. This is why option-based thinking is ideal for high risk environments like new products or startup ventures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22519/image/sideprojects2-1b.gif"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Success on the Side&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So start thinking of your side project as a real option. It gives you a ticket to play and enables you to learn your way into a real business. Think of the possible outcomes for your side project:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;It starts getting traction: you can call in your option and ramp up your commitment, either with your own money or someone else’s, with a much greater certainty of success.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It needs major changes: pat yourself on the back for learning something valuable without over-committing to the wrong path. Now ask whether you wish to pay a bit more to extend your option and evolve your product idea, based on your new insights.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It is fundamentally flawed: cheer yourself up by recognizing that you’ve just saved yourself a lot of wasted effort and pain down the track. Better to know sooner rather than later that it won’t work, because your time is the most scarce and precious resource of all.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In other words, the measure of progress for your side project is not revenue or scale, but useful knowledge gained. As you learn, you reduce the risk of pursuing the core opportunity and make it more likely that you can convert your side project into a compelling and viable product.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/3032394/hit-the-ground-running/spotifys-design-lead-on-why-side-projects-should-be-stupid"&gt;Examples&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.rudebaguette.com/2012/01/09/start-working-side-project/"&gt;successful side projects&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;include&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://basecamp.com/"&gt;Basecamp&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.fastcolabs.com/3026699/inside-the-swedish-gaming-mafia-that-produced-minecraft-and-candy-crush-saga"&gt;Minecraft&lt;/a&gt;, Twitter,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://blog.uber.com/2010/12/22/ubers-founding/"&gt;Uber&lt;/a&gt;, Craigslist, and Gmail. &amp;nbsp;What’s more, research suggests that the simple act of working on creative side projects is&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://open.bufferapp.com/side-projects-creative-hobbies/"&gt;good for you&lt;/a&gt;, with participants likely to be more helpful, collaborative, productive and relaxed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What’s Your Side Project?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’re here on Tuts+, chances are that you’re someone who is committed to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://webdesign.tutsplus.com/articles/lifelong-education-is-for-everyone--cms-22039"&gt;lifelong learning&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and creating interesting things. You may be happy with selling your skills as an employee or freelancer&amp;nbsp;(or just learning for the pure joy of it)&amp;nbsp;and those are perfectly reasonable paths to take.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But if you are someone who dreams about creating a product or starting a new venture, I hope that this perspective encourages you to think about the relative merits of going all-in at the outset versus starting with a side project and evolving it over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’d love to hear your experiences and thoughts on this, so please feel free to contribute to the conversation by commenting below.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <media:content url="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22519/preview_image/sideprojects4b.png" medium="image" width="200" height="138"/>
        <published>2014-09-25T06:10:44.000Z</published>
        <updated>2014-09-25T06:10:44.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Xavier Russo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>tag:photography.tutsplus.com,2005:PostPresenter/cms-22520</id>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://webdesign.tutsplus.com/articles/5-things-i-learned-from-the-tuts-translation-project--cms-22520"/>
        <title>5 Things I Learned From the Tuts+ Translation Project</title>
        <content type="html">&lt;figure class="post_image"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22520/image/translation2-1b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;We recently launched the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://tutsplus.com/translate-for-us"&gt;Tuts+ Translation Project&lt;/a&gt;, an initiative which has seen the Tuts+ community rally to translate, publish and share our tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The response has been overwhelming; not only from readers who are thrilled to see our content in their native tongue, but also from people across the whole world who have volunteered to help. In the last few months I’ve been working with a large team of individuals, who’ve so far published over 200 translations in sixteen languages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And we’ve barely scratched the surface.&amp;nbsp;During the course of this project I’ve learned a great many things, about language and people. Here are my top five!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="sectionnum"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; My Written English Isn’t Globally Understandable&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve written my fair share of tutorials and articles, usually spattered with a healthy dose of British hyperbole and obscure comedy references. I enjoy writing that way. And some of those who read what I write enjoy it too. Possibly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It turns out, however, that confusing metaphors sometimes confuse people. I realised this when Thoriq (whilst translating&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://webdesign.tutsplus.com/articles/a-beginners-guide-to-pairing-fonts--webdesign-5706"&gt;A Beginner’s Guide to Pairing Fonts&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;into Indonesian) asked me what typography had to do with wedding speeches. Thoriq speaks fluent English, but if he’s baffled by my quirky writing, how many others are coming unstuck?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hereby swear that, from this day forth, I shall endeavour to write my tutorials in non-cryptic, accessible English.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="sectionnum"&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt; Voice and Tone Are Complex&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tuts+ Instructors are given guidelines to assist in producing tutorials and courses for us, including guides to writing. We have a Voice and Tone document suggesting that tutorials should be written in a “friendly but not sloppy” way, that they should come across as “confident but not cocky”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When more languages are added into the mix, these guidelines are even more important, as many of our German translators have pointed out. English, you see, is fairly unique in that it lacks any specific formal or informal speech. Most other languages use a formal and an informal “you” for addressing individuals; the difference, say, between talking to a friend as opposed to your Bank Manager. German goes even further by having four distinct ways of doing this. Its detailed scale of politeness applies equally to objects, not just persons, so even the word “the” can communicate attitude. It can get pretty complicated!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the record, we’ve opted to translate all our tutorials “informally”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="sectionnum"&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt; Text Within Images is Bad&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For some time we’ve made it a policy to avoid text within images in our tutorials, instead placing captions underneath. This keeps things visually consistent and has some SEO benefits as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that we’re translating tutorials, keeping images free from textual content is more important than ever! Text within images is bad. Bad, bad, bad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="sectionnum"&gt;4.&lt;/span&gt; Translators Make Great Proof-Readers&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re proud of our editing standards at Tuts+, but sometimes mistakes slip through the net. Occasionally readers will leave comments, pointing out typos, but if mistakes manage to get past them you can be sure our translators will catch them!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been bowled over by the perfectionism our translators display, not just in their own translations, but by suggesting improvements to the original content too. Thanks go to Nicolas Devaux, who, whilst translating&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://code.tutsplus.com/tutorials/28-html5-features-tips-and-techniques-you-must-know--net-13520"&gt;28 HTML5 Features, Tips, and Techniques you Must Know&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;into French, pointed out that &amp;lt;hgroup&amp;gt; has been deprecated and should no longer be used! We’ve since updated the article.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span class="sectionnum"&gt;5.&lt;/span&gt; Google Translate Isn’t Good Enough&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, Google Translate is an incredible tool. And, thanks to the massive community which keeps it updated, it’s improving on an hourly basis. However, it isn’t good enough for our purposes—we can’t rely on automated translation to provide accurate, multilingual versions of our content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve mistakenly relied on Google Translate a couple of times during this project (just for missing details) but each time have quickly been shown the error of my ways!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wdtuts"&gt;@wdtuts&lt;/a&gt; 中國（繁體）actually means China (Traditional). If you mean Chinese (Traditional), it should be 中文（繁體）.&lt;/p&gt;— Andrews Ang (@kongnir) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kongnir/status/463725426175520768"&gt;May 6, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;The Last Word&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ll leave you with a quote, taken from a conversation I had with a translation volunteer. He says it far better than I can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I believe that teaching people all over the world is very important … everyone must be able to learn new things no matter where they live." -&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/+RecepEmul/posts"&gt;Recep Emul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Get Involved!&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to know more about the translation project, have suggestions or perhaps even want to get involved yourself, you’ll find all the details you need on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://tutsplus.com/translate-for-us"&gt;translation information page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <media:content url="https://cms-assets.tutsplus.com/uploads/users/8/posts/22520/preview_image/translation2-1c.jpg" medium="image" width="200" height="138"/>
        <published>2014-09-12T06:28:11.000Z</published>
        <updated>2014-09-12T06:28:11.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Yates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>